Hi, here is our Email automation workflow on n8n
First, we must 'Execute workflow' to get started
Now, this is an interface where user initiates a trigger, to write email
User can write their own or choose from examples
User clicks on Generate button to start writing
Now, we come back to watch our workflow running
Note, all nodes turning green, and 'Wrokflow executed successfully' message
Now, we come back to see our draft in Gmail
and... here it lands, safely
let's open to see what it has for us, okay
Now, come back to our n8n workflow
'Execute workflow' to try another instance
Moving to our trigger interface for user
Dr. Istanbul's Email Agent is making things happen
Let's email Jane for meeting follow-up
Now we click on 'Generate to continue
Let's watch our 'backend' workflow running
Note, the nodes turning green
our agent is busy in your service...
and..., here we go, 'Workflow executed successfully'
let's see if it really executed
Congratulations! here it comes
Let's minimize our previous one
Open new one, and yes, here it is
Now, we want to do something different
'Execute workflow' once more
Let's move to Dr. Istanbul's Email Agent interface
This time we will write trigger by ourselves, no examples
I hope Ali will be happy with this
Let's watch our workflow running
It works hard, good boy!
and... yes, 'Workflow executed successfully'
Now, time to make confirmation
Refresh the Gmail drafts tab
Yes, we have email draft for our Ali here
Minimize the last one, and open the newest
Yes, this email requests Ali for report
Now, let's understand the science (or tech) 'backend'
All our workflow nodes are important
However, we're interested in how our emails were actually drafted
So, we put our dynamic prompt here in 'HTTP Request' node
Open it, and you will see in URL field that it uses an API for OpenAI
This AI drafts emails for us when we trigger via interface message
Let's seen on left how we our trigger message arrives here
See our trigger from 'Dr. Istanbul's Email Agent' for email to Ali
The user trigger was recieved by 'Webhook' node on left
Now let's look below how HTTP processes this trigger
Here, we have saved a dynamic prompt in JSON format
Look at the prompt carefully, and you'll see beautiful expression
On the right, you can see AI drafted email "content" as output
Thank you for watching 'Dr. Istanbul's Email Agent' in action!
See you again, with more serious AI by our very own 'Dr. Istanbul'